

Long P. Hoang



RESEARCH INTEREST

My research focus has been improving the optimization techniques for Multi-Task deep neural networks, profiling the trade-off between the conflicting tasks, and investigating their effectiveness in large-scale problems such as Recommender Systems, Large Language Models.

EDUCATION

PhD Singapore University of Technology and Design (SUTD)

09/2024 - Present

Academic advisor: Assoc. Prof. Lu Wei

• Major: Computer Science

Bachelor Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

08/2018 - 09/2022

· Academic advisor: Dr. Thang N. Tran

• Major: Mathematics and Informatics. CPA: 3.11/4.00 (Rank 18 out of 94 in my department)

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Quang-Huy Nguyen[†], **Long P. Hoang**[†], Vu V. Hoang, Dung D. Le, Controllable Expensive Multi-objective Optimization with Warm-starting Gaussian Process, *arXiv* preprint *arXiv*:2311.15297, 2024
- [2] Tuan A. Tran[†], **Long P. Hoang**[†], Dung D. Le, Thang N. Tran, A Framework for Controllable Pareto Front Learning with Completed Scalarization Functions and its Applications, *Neural Networks*, 2024
- [3] Long P. Hoang, Dung D. Le, Tuan A. Tran, Thang N. Tran, Improving Pareto Front Learning via Multi-Sample Hypernetworks, In Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2023
- [4] Anh T. Ho, Tuan A. Tran, **Long P. Hoang**, Ha H. Le, Thang N. Tran, Multi Deep Learning Model for Building Footprint Extraction from High-Resolution Remote Sensing Image, *In Intelligent Systems and Networks*, 2022

EXPERIENCE

NLP Engineer FTech Co., Ltd

Developing a General Natural Language Understanding tool for Vietnamese

12/2023 - 06/2024

- Developed a NER model recognizing 9 popular entities for Vietnamese with 0.91 f1-score using Transfer Learning and Adversarial Training
- Constructed an Entity Linking model that obtained a 0.85 accuracy without a degradation in the performance of the NER model
- Reduced half of the VRAM of the LLM Mistral-7b using SmoothQuant

Research Assistant

College of Engineering and Computer Science, VinUniversity

Advisor: Assist. Prof. Dung D. Le

Controllable Multi-Objective Recommender System

10/2022 - 10/2023

[†]Co-First Author

• Developed a new framework for Multi-Objective Recommendation which considers a variety of criteria, including fairness, robustness, novelty in special scenarios such as cold start, adversarial attack,...

Expensive Multi-Objective Optimization

03/2023 - 10/2023

- Built high-dimensional Bayesian Optimization methods by estimating the gradient of Black-Box functions
- Approximated the entire trade-off curve of black-box objects using Pareto Front Learning with Hypernetworks computed by Gaussian Processes

Profiling the Pareto Front in Multi-Task Learning

02/2022 - 10/2022

 Proposed a novel method named Multi-Sample Hypernetwork to approximate the entire trade-off curve of conflicting objectives (accepted to AAAI 2023)

Teaching Assistant

02/2022 – 07/2022

 Supported Assist. Prof. Dung D. Le during the lecture class and held office hours in class "Database Concepts and Skills for Big Data", AY 2021-2022

Undergraduate Research Assistant

School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, HUST

Advisor: Dr. Thang N. Tran

Multi-Objective Optimization with Completed Scalarizations

02/2022 - 02/2023

• Proposed and proved the convergence of a new framework for Pareto Multi-Task Learning with Scalarization Functions in the pseudo-convex and quasiconvex assumptions (accepted to the journal Neural Networks)

Building Footprint Extraction from Remote Sensing Images

07/2021 - 10/2022

 Developed a two-stage framework, which combines U2-Net and Mask-CNN, to increase 1.8-2.5% mAP, mAR for Building Footprint Extraction, especially effective in populated areas (accepted to ICISN 2022)

PERSONAL SKILLS

Languages IELTS 6.0 (L 5.5, R 6.5, W 6.0, S 6.5), GRE (V 139, Q 161, A 3.0)

Programming Languages Python, C

Frameworks Latex, Pytorch, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Docker

ADWARDS & CERTIFICATES

- 3rd Prize (Grooo International company's sponsorship) in Scientific Research Student Conference at School of Mathematics and Informatics, Hanoi University of Science and Technology, Jul 2022
- Certificate of Completion of Developer Circles Vietnam Innovation Challenge in Data Science, sponsored by Facebook, Nov 2020

REFERENCES

1. Assoc. Prof. Lu Wei (Ph.D), Information Systems Technology and Design

luwei@sutd.edu.sg

- Assist. Prof. Dung D. Le (Ph.D), College of Engineering and Computer Science, VinUniversity
 dung.ld@vinuni.edu.vn
- 3. **Dr. Thang N. Tran** (Ph.D), School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics, Hanoi University of Science and Technology *thang.tranngoc@hust.edu.vn*